Derek Misler

Software Engineer & UI/UX Designer

I am a software engineer with a design background and 15+ years of experience building exceptional, high-quality websites and applications. I also have tons of UI/UX experience, and a surprisingly large knowledge of typography (seriously, let's talk about it). I think all developers should study design, and I believe having this well-rounded education makes me a stronger engineer.

Hello!

Brooklyn, NY 828-273-6943 derekmisler@gmail.com

For more experience information and contact details, as well as a portfolio of work, visit derekmisler.com.

Education

Appalachian State University

BFA - Graphic Design

2005-2009

I chose to study graphic design in an arts department. I already had a grasp on front-end web development techniques and continued to study them during this time, but the curriculum path I chose focused on web design while also teaching color theory, typography, and layout design in a group setting.

<u>Skills</u>

| AWS | **** | React-Native | **** |
|-----------|------|--------------|------|
| | | | |
| Adobe CS | **** | React/Redux | **** |
| Aurelia | **** | Angular | **** |
| CSS3 | **** | DevOps | **** |
| ES6/7 | **** | PHP | **** |
| Firebase | **** | Ruby/Rails | **** |
| HTML5 | **** | Go | *** |
| LESS/Sass | **** | Java | *** |
| Node.js | **** | Python | **** |

Career

Transfix

Staff Software Engineer

2016-Present

Refactored web app from Rails, to Aurelia (a terrific JS framework), and finally landing on React/Redux.

Refactored our public site from Wordpress to Jade, a great (but extinct) static site templating language.

Developed an internal library for creating web (React/Redux) apps, mobile (React Native) apps, and shared modules (NPM).

Brand-new CI/CD pipeline (CircleCI).

Created standards for networking configurations, CSS and JS syntax linting, and automated testing.

Developed our web networking standards, using AWS tools, including all of our deployment configurations, client-side security, and multi-region failover.

Technical lead on the creation of our internal component/design pattern library.

Rebuilt our Android and iOS apps using React Native.

Grew a team of cross-functional engineers and designers to continue the work.

Asheville Convention & Visitors Bureau

Web Manager/Developer

2011-2015

As the only developer on staff, my job was to maintain our entire web presence. Starting with a .NET-backed site, I oversaw two redesigns: first a Coldfusion site and more recently with a responsive site that was developed primarily in Node.js on the back-end and a custom JS framework, Goatee, on the front-end. I also developed two long-form, award-winning web apps

Houser Shoes, Inc.

Developer/Designer/Photographer

2010-2011

I was part of a 3 person team that redesigned their e-commerce website with Magento, which utilized primarily PHP and MySQL and was tied to their inventory and accounting systems.

Freelance

Developer/Designer

2009-Present

A lot of branding at first, but eventually full-time web development. Mostly Shopify, SquareSpace, or Wordpress in the past, but I recently had a chance to work on a custom Go-backed UI library.